kara no kokoro wo terasu mono wa nani?
What brightens up an empty heart?
sakebi tsuzukeru hikari todoku made
I will keep on singing until the light reaches you
falling through the cracks kurayami e ochiteku
Falling through the cracks, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me the story of your life mada michi no tochuu
Tell me the story of your life, We're still on our way
anata o watashi wa zettai akiramenai
I will never give up on you
osaerarenai shoudou nanigenai hibi wa aijyou
Urges I can't suppress, I live for the ordinary days
natsukashii kaze ni furimukeba itsud
When I turn my cheek to a nostalgic wind
emo anata no koe ga suru yo
I always hear your voice
underdog wa wander around
Underdog will Wander around
mawari michi shitemo nigeru yori mashi yo
Even if I take the long way around,
it's better than running away
jibun de jibun o shinjirare nakucha dare wo shinjiru no?
If I can't learn to believe in myself,
then who can I believe in?
hikari ni sono te kazase
Hold up your hand to the light
shining through the clouds kurayami e ochiteku
Shining through the clouds, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me what is on your mind hateshinai yume wo
Tell me what is on your mind,
Chasing the never ending dream
oikake bokura wa zettai akiramenai
We will never give up
kotae no nai jinsei ni kujike sou ni naru kedo
Discouraged by a life without answers, but I...
don’t give it up! keep it up! turn it upside down!
Don't give it up! Keep it up! Turn it upside down!
kokoro wa tsunagatteru yo tatoe tooku hanaretemo
Our hearts will always be connected,
no matter how far apart we may be
tomo ni tomo ni ikiteyukou
Let's share this life together
Orochimaru...
(自来也)大蛇丸。
I wonder what that was?
なんだかね イテテッ。
I thought it was a kitty
scuttling about, oh well...
ネコちゃんがチョロチョロしてたと
思ったけどね…。
BATHS
Oh!
What a sight!
お～ いい眺めだのぉ～。
Boobs.
Lots of boobs.
(自来也)オッパイ いっぱい…。
This is great!
いい気分！
Is this what you called me out for?
(大蛇丸)わざわざ呼ぶから
何かと思ったら…。
I'm leaving.
Hey...
僕はもう帰る。
おい おい 声がでかいのぉ。
Don't talk so loud.
You want a look?
ヘヘッ お前も見るか？
Oh, lots of butts too!
お～ お尻もいっぱいだってえの。
おっ お～！
Hey, Orochimaru...
おい 大蛇丸。
ん… 大蛇丸!?
Orochimaru?
You... pervy brat!
この エロガキ！
Hot! Hot! Hot!
(自来也)アヂ～ッ！ アチッ アチッ アチッ。
Aw c'mon, hot water, really?!
Hot!
フフフッ。
熱湯はなしだろ アヂ～ッ！
This is the plan.
You disguise yourself and
make a move on Tsunade.
(自来也)作戦はこうじゃ。
I'll appear just in time,
and chase you away.
お前が変装して 綱手に絡む。
すると わしが グッドタイミングで現れて
お前を追い払う。
And Tsunade will say,
"Oh Jiraiya, you're so amazing!"
すると綱手は 自来也君 すてき
となるわけだのぉ。
What's the point to all of this?
そんなことに
どんな意味があるの？
I don't understand it.
理解できない。
It has deep significance to me.
(自来也)
わしには意味があるんじゃ。
Very deep significance.
深～い意味がのぉ。
She's close by...
近いよ。
Huh?!
え？
Damn it!
If... if only... I'd folded back then!
(綱手)クソ～ あれだな
あのとき おりてたら…。
Nah... gambling isn't that simple.
いや 賭けは
そんな簡単なことじゃない。
That was that and...
あれは あれで あり。
Probably...
I'm sure...
ん… たぶん あり。 きっと あり。
Yeah, it was the snap.
ん～ そうね
あのときのスナップが…。
The way the dice rolled.
こう… サイコロの回転を…。
That moment seals
whether you win or lose.
ここが勝負ってときにこそ
こう スナップが…。
Yeah, the snap...
Huh?!
Who are you?
ん！ 何者だい？
I'm in a bad mood right now.
(綱手)こっちは今 イライラしてんだ。
If you try anything...
I'll kill you!
(綱手)
ふざけたことすると 殺すぞ！
うぉ～！
(大蛇丸)うわぁ～！
Tsunade!
A-Are you all right?
綱手！ だ 大丈夫かのぉ？
I'm here now, so...
わしが来たからには…。
don't worry...
もう… 安心…。
Okay?
だ… のぉ。
Huh? What're you doing here?
(綱手)はぁ？ なんでお前が
ここにいるんだい？
Actually... I mean, you see...
実はのぉ… いや その…。
You're... looking...
awfully sexy...
今夜のお前は そこはかとなく
色っぽい… のぉ。
tonight.
Hey, Jiraiya...
I'm leaving.
おい 自来也… 私は帰る。
Just what are you guys up to?
アハハハハハ！
何してんだ？ お前たち。
(自来也)フフフフフ… アハハハハ！
アハ… アハハハハ！
ヒヒヒヒヒ… エヘ…。
It gets so cold when night falls.
(綱手)さすがに
日が落ちると冷え込むな。
They won't attack us tonight.
今夜は もう
やつらも襲ってこんだろう。
Hey...
Why don't we talk about
our dreams tonight?
なぁ！ 今宵は わしらの夢でも
語り合わんかのぉ？
Dreams?
If you have any dreams, that is.
(大蛇丸)夢？
まぁ 夢があればの話だがのぉ。
I thought all you only think
about is pervy stuff.
(綱手)エロいことしか
頭にないと思ってたが…。
Jiraiya, it's an interesting topic
for you to bring up.
自来也！ 今夜は
おもしろいことを言うね。
Well then, let's start with you, Tsunade.
(自来也)では 綱手から
話してもらおうかのぉ。
Me?
私か？
I want to see the world
from one corner to the other.
私は この世界を
隅から隅まで見てみたい。
The world, you say?!
That's a bold dream!
(自来也)世界とな！
大きく出たのぉ。
I'm going to win at
every casino there is!
フフッ！
世界のカジノで勝ちまくるのさ。
So?
What's your dream?
で… お前の夢はなんなのさ？
My dream is, perhaps...
うん わしの夢は…。
to protect you during your travels.
世界を旅する綱手の
護衛でもするかのぉ。
No thanks.
(綱手)それは お断りするよ。
Orochimaru!
Open up and talk about yourself
once in a while.
(自来也)大蛇丸 お前も たまには
自分のことを話さんかのぉ。
Dreams...
(大蛇丸)夢…。
I don't have a dream.
You're such a boring guy.
夢なんか ない。
(自来也)アハハハハ！
おぬし ほんに つまらん男よのぉ。
Leave him alone!
To each his own.
(綱手)絡むな！
人はそれぞれだよ。
Besides, there are things
we want to keep to ourselves—
それに 話したくないことも…。
I want to master ninjutsu.
忍術を極めたい。
And become stronger than anyone.
そして 誰よりも強くなる。
Oh? For what purpose?
(自来也)ほう… 何のためにじゃ？
For what purpose?
何のため？
I've never thought
about such a thing.
そんなこと 考えたこともないわ。
I see...
That's so like you.
なるほど… フン！ お前らしいのぉ。
Don't talk like you know me.
わかったようなことを言うわね。
Oh! I know!
Wouldn't it be great to write
about what we see and hear
おぉ そうじゃ！
旅の見聞を書くのも いいのぉ。
on our world travels, Tsunade?
You can go by yourself.
綱手と世界を旅して…。
お前は１人で行け！
That would be...
それは…。
so...
寂しい…。
lonely.
のぉ。
うぉ～っ！
ハハハハハ！ おっ…。
はぁ～っ！
うぉ～っ！
They're coming one after another!
Yeah!
(自来也)続々 来るのぉ。
(大蛇丸)あぁ。
I'll pulverize them!
(綱手)ぶっ飛ばしてやる！
Yeah...
(カカシ)ああ そうか
これで最後ね。
This is the last.
Thank you for the food.
いただきます。
I think I've mastered
nitsuke dishes.
うん。
煮付けはもう極めたかな。
SIMMERED FISH [NITSUKE]
EVERYDAY RECIPES FOR FISH
I guess I'll try meuniere next.
次は ムニエルでしょ。
I'm leaving.
いってきます。
Hey, Dad... Dad!
ねぇねぇ
お父さん お父さん。
Oh well, sure, what the hell.
Yay... yay!
しかたないな。
わ～い わ～い！
Isn't that nice?
ICHIRAKU RAMEN
This place is great!
(カカシ)え～い やっ！
(ヒルゼン)ふん！
(カカシ)うわ！
Kakashi, you are terrific.
(ヒルゼン)カカシは すごいな。
If I let my guard down
even for a moment,
I think you'd beat me.
わしでも気を抜いたら
一本とられるかもしれん。
Thank you.
Isn't Kakashi great?
(カカシ)どうも。
Well, his dad is a genius.
(リン)すごいよね カカシ君。
(オビト)あいつの父ちゃんも
天才忍者だからな。
Even if he doesn't do anything,
he probably still has the skills.
何もしなくったって
才能あるんじゃね？
Anyway, I'm an Uchiha.
まあ 俺はうちはだし
もちろん頑張るしさ。
I'll keep doing my best.
I bet he's... a closet pervert.
あいつさ
きっとムッツリスケベだぜ。
You're great, Kakashi.
Think so?
カカシ君 すごいね！
そうか？
Do you practice all the time?
Seriously, you're amazing.
いつも練習してるの？
本当すごいよ！
Not really...
I kind of read a few books.
別に…
本は少し読んだかな。
ULTIMATE TECHNIQUES
All right!
う～ん よし。
He's... He's kinda amazing.
なんか なんかすげえ。
Oh!
あ！
Amazing...
Kakashi, you're amazing!
すげえ！
カカシ お前 すげえよ。
Come on out.
I made a lot.
出て来いよ 多めに作ったから。
So you might as well stay and eat.
食べていけばいいでしょ。
You caught me!
エヘヘ！
バレちゃった。
I'm sorry...
ごめんなさい。
え？ え～！
So Kakashi, you live by yourself?
(リン)ハッ！
(オビト)アハハ！
Hey! That thing you do,
that "whoosh-whoosh" is great.
カカシ君って
１人で暮らしてるの？
あれだな お前のあれ
ビュビュッてやるの おもしろいな。
Yeah... that "whoosh-whoosh."
It's amazing.
うん ビュビュッて すごいね。
Think so?
そうか？
It's so cute...
What is this, Kakashi?
(オビト)かわいい。
(リン)カカシ君 これって？
River fish meunière...
Kakashi-style.
(カカシ)川魚のムニエル カカシ風。
– Thank you for the food!
(３人)いただきます！
Kakashi, this tastes really good!
カカシ君 これ すっごくおいしいよ。
It's like the food you get
in a restaurant.
お店で食べる料理みたい。
Yeah, this is great!
You're amazing...
確かに。
お前 すげえよ。
Think so?
Are you gonna become a chef?
(カカシ)そうか。
お前 料理人になるのか？
Huh? I doubt it.
え？ そんなわけないでしょ。
I guess not, huh?
(オビト)それもそうか。
I'm leaving.
いってきます。
Hey, Kakashi!
お～い カカシ。
ハァ ハァ…。
The food last night was great!
昨日のごちそう うまかったぜ。
It was really delicious.
本当に うまかったよ。
Hey, are you listening?
あっ ねぇ 聞いてる？
Yeah...
ICHIRAKU RAMEN
あぁ。
Hey, this place is good.
It's looks delicious. I wanna try it.
おっ ここ うまいんだぜ。
Hey, hold on!
うまそう！
あ ちょちょ… おい 待てよ。
Let's go here next time.
Yeah.
今度 来ようぜ。
あぁ。
Kakashi...
Do you want to spend the springtime
of your youth with me?
(ガイ)カカシ君 僕と青春しないかい？
Springtime of youth?
You are my eternal rival...
My man of destiny!
青春？
キミは
僕の永遠のライバルになる 運命の人。
はぁ。
Come on.
Fight me!
さあ 勝負だ！
Sorry, no.
(カカシ)それは 勘弁だな。
Here I come!
いくぞ！ うりゃ～！
Instant kill...
うわっ！
A-Amazing.
(ガイ)瞬殺か… さすがだよ。
My eternal rival is... amazing.
我が永遠のライバル… さすが だ…。
I'm home.
ただいま。
Oh yeah...
あ… そうか。
It's tomorrow.
明日か。
I'm leaving.
いってきます。
Dad...
父さん。
You broke the rules
for your friends' sake, right?
父さんは 仲間のために
掟を破ったんでしょ？
I've made friends too.
俺にも仲間ができたよ。
But I'll never be like you, Dad.
でも
俺は父さんみたいにはならない。
I'll obey the rules.
掟は守る。
I'll see you later, Dad.
父さん じゃあまた。
I'm leaving.
いってきます。
'Morning!
Are you feeling better?
おはよう！ もう体はいいの？
You were absent yesterday and
it's no fun when
you're not around, Kakashi.
昨日 休んじゃうからさ。
Is that right?
カカシがいないと つまんねえよ。
そうか。
Kakashi!
(ガイ)カカシ君！
この前はキミに敗れたが→
I lost to you last time...
But that was the Might Guy
of the past.
それは以前までのマイト・ガイだ。
The newly reborn Might Guy
will never lose to you!
生まれ変わったマイト・ガイは
決してキミに負けたりはしない！
Your face is still swollen.
顔 まだ腫れてるけど。
Of course!
The springtime of youth
never comes to an end!
そうさ 青春に終わりはないのさ。
The springtime of youth...
(カカシ)青春って…。
Come on, let's fight!
さあ 勝負だ！
Oh!
Kakashi!
(オビト)おっ！
(リン)カカシ君。
Oh! Guy's keeping up!
Do it, Kakashi!
Come on, Kakashi!
The light... of spring... will...
never... wane!
Maybe not.
– The end!
sayonara arigatou
Good bye, thank you
koko kara habatakou
We're flying away from here
karappo no tenohira nigirishimete sa
Our empty hands squeezed tight
namida ja nagasenai tashika na omoi ga atta
Not even tears could wash away these feelings
kagiri aru sekai e fumidasu yo
We're stepping out into a world with limits
ashita moshi bokura ga koko kara kietemo
Even if we're suddenly gone tomorrow
kawari nante hoka ni mo irundesho?
There would be others who could replace us, right?
jishin nante hajime kara motte wa inai kedo
We were never confident to begin with
akiramerarenainda
But we can't seem to give it up
isso
What if...
zenbu o suteraretara
We just abandon everything and call it quits?
motto raku ni naru ka na
Would things be easier?
sonna imeeji hitotsu de
That image alone
matataku ma ni toozakatteyuku mirai
was enough to grab on hold to the future
dakishimeta
that was quickly fading away
sayonara arigatou
Good bye, thank you
muchuu de habatakou
We're flying away with everything we got
kagiri aru sekai no sono naka ni
Into a world with limits
sayonara arigatou sayonara arigatou
Good bye, thank you
kanarazu mata aeru sono basho de
We'll definitely meet again, back there
The next episode is all
about Sasuke, ya' know!
After the last battle,
where I clashed with Naruto,
へぇ～ ガイもやるじゃん。
and after the Fourth
Great Ninja War ended,
I went on a journey to
atone for my sins.
(ガイ)は～っ！
あっ。
With the Sharingan in my right eye,
and the Rinnegan in my left...
カカシ いけいけ～！
What future will
these eyes see now?
These eyes that once
only saw darkness?
カカシ君 ファイト！
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Sasuke's Story: Sunrise, Part 1:
The Exploding Human."
(ガイ)せ… 青春の光は→
決して… 決して消えたりは
しないのです！
This is a story about my atonement.
(カカシ)そうかもね。